《回到未来》
(布朗的宅邸被拆毁)
(布朗的财产卖给了开发商)
十月是清点货物换季的时节
October is inventory time,
所以现在丰田汽车
so right now, Statler Toyota
正在降价
is making the best deals of the year
你再也找不到
on all 1985-model Toyotas.
比丰田1985更好的车
You won't find a better car
价钱便宜 服务周到
at a better price with better service anywhere in Hill Valley.
这就是山谷镇的丰田
That's Statler Toyota in downtown Hill Valley.
参议院今天将对此投票表决
The Senate is expected to vote on this today.
其他方面新闻 太平洋核子研究所的高级官员
In other news, officials at the Pacific Nuclear research facility
否认了两周前 一箱装有核材料钚的箱子
have denied the rumor that a case of missing plutonium
在保险箱中被人盗走的传闻
was in fact stolen from their vault two weeks ago.
而一利比亚恐怖组织声称
A Libyan terrorist group had claimed responsibility
对此偷盗事件负责
for the alleged theft.
然而 该高级官员却说
However, officials now attribute
完全是清点错误
the discrepancy to a simple clerical error.
调查此事的FBI 目前没有表态
The FBI, which is investigating the matter, had no comment.
(狗食)
(爱因斯坦)
嘿 博士?
Hey, Doc?
博士?
Doc?
喂 有人在家吗?
Hello! Anybody home?
爱因斯坦 到这来
Einstein, come here, boy.
出什么事了? 老天!
What's going on? Oh, God.
我的天哪
Oh, Jesus!
闻起来真恶心! 他在哪啊?
That is disgusting. Where the hell is he?
(钚 小心搬运)
哇
Whoa!
摇滚起来
Rock 'n' roll.
马丁 是你吗?
Marty, is that you?
嘿 博士 你在哪?
Hey. Hey, Doc. Where are you?
谢天谢地 总算找到你了
Thank God I've found you.
听着 你可否在凌晨 1:15到"双松购物超市"来见我?
Listen, can you meet me at Twin Pines Mall tonight at 1:15?
我有了新突破 需要你的帮助
I made a major breakthrough, and I'll need your assistance.
等一等 凌晨 1:15?
Wait a minute. 1:15 in the morning?
是的
Yeah.
出什么事了?
Doc, what's going on?
- 整整一星期你去哪了? - 工作
- Where you been all week? - Working.
爱因斯坦呢? 和你在一起吗?
Where's Einstein? Is he with you?
是的 它就在这
Yeah, he's right here.
博士 你的仪器整个星期都是开着的
You know, Doc, you left your equipment on all week.
我的仪器? 我告诉你 马丁
My equipment. That reminds me, Marty.
别接通那个扩音器
You better not hook up to the amplifier.
会超载的!
There's a slight possibility of overload.
好的 我记住了
Yeah. I'll keep that in mind.
好 咱们晚上见 别忘了是凌晨
Good. I'll see you tonight. Don't forget now.
1:15 双胞胎松林购物广场
1:15 a.m., Twin Pines Mall.
好的
Right.
我讨厌敲钟声!
Are those my clocks I hear?
我知道 8点正了
Yeah, it's 8:00.
我迟到了! 我还得工作呢!
Perfect! My experiment worked!
所有的钟都整整慢了 25 分钟
They're all exactly 25 minutes slow!
等一等 博士
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, Doc.
你是说 现在是 8:25 ?
Are you telling me that it's 8:25?
没错!
Precisely.
该死! 我上学要迟到了
Damn! I'm late for school.
(钚 小心搬运)
(山谷镇)
(请投现任市长 戈尔迪·威尔逊 一票)
- 嗨 詹妮弗 - 马丁 别走这条路
- Jennifer. - Marty, don't go this way.
斯特里克兰正在找你
Strickland's looking for you.
如果你被逮着 就是4次迟到了
If you get caught, it'll be four tardies in a row.
好了 现在安全了
All right, come on. I think we're safe.
你知道 这次不是我的错
You know, this time it wasn't my fault.
是博士把钟调慢了25分钟
The doc set all his clocks 25 minutes slow.
博士?
Doc?
你还在跟 埃米特·布朗博士混呢 对吗 麦佛莱?
Am I to understand you're still hanging around with Dr. Emmett Brown, McFly?
一张迟到通知单给你 帕克小姐
Tardy slip for you, Miss Parker.
一张给你 麦佛莱 共4次迟到
And one for you, McFly. I believe that makes four in a row.
给你个免费的忠告 年轻人
Let me give you a nickel's worth of free advice, young man.
那个所谓的布朗博士 是危险人物 一个真正的疯子
This so-called Dr. Brown is dangerous. He's a real nutcase.
和他在一起 你会惹上大麻烦
You hang around with him, you're gonna end up in big trouble.
是的 先生
Ooh. Yes, sir.
你的态度有问题 麦佛莱! 你是个懒散的家伙
You got a real attitude problem, McFly. You're a slacker.
当年他在这
You remind me of your father when he went here.
也是个懒散的家伙
He was a slacker, too.
我现在可以走了吗 斯特里克兰先生?
Can I go now, Mr. Strickland?
我听说你的乐队在放学后
I noticed your band is on the roster
要参加舞会演奏测试
for the dance auditions after school today.
为何要参加 麦佛莱? 你门都没有
Why even bother, McFly? You don't have a chance.
你太像你老爸
You're too much like your old man.
麦佛莱一族 从来没
No McFly ever amounted to anything
在山谷镇的历史里留名
in the history of Hill Valley.
是吗? 历史就要改变了
Yeah, well, history is gonna change.
下一个
Next, please.
大伙 准备摇滚
Okay, guys, let's rock 'n roll.
(舞会演奏测试)
好了
All right.
我们是针头乐队
We're the... We're the Pinheads.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
好了 谢谢 谢谢你们
Okay, that's enough. Thank you, fellas.
停下 小伙子们
Hold it, fellas.
恐怕你们的声音太大了
I'm afraid you're just too darn loud.
下一个
Next, please.
谁是下一个?
Bring up the next group, please.
竞选连任的戈尔迪·威尔逊市长
Re-elect Mayor "Goldie" Wilson.
他代表着进步
Progress is his middle name.
真不敢相信!
"Too loud." I can't believe it.
为什么 不给我们机会在人们面前演奏?
I'm never gonna get a chance to play in front of anybody.
马丁 被拒绝一次 并不是世界末日
Marty, one rejection isn't the end of the world.
我想 也许我该放弃音乐
I just don't think I'm cut out for music.
可你很棒 马丁 真的很棒
But you're good, Marty. You're really good,
而且你的试听带也相当不错
and this audition tape of yours is great.
你该把它寄给唱片公司
You've gotta send it in to the record company.
- 就像博士说的那样 - 我知道 我知道
- It's like Doc's always saying. - Yeah, I know. I know.
"只要你一心一意
"If you put your mind to it,
做什么都成"
you can accomplish anything."
这是个很好的忠告
That's good advice, Marty.
那好吧 詹尼弗
All right, okay, Jennifer.
如果我寄出的带子他们不喜欢?
What if I send in the tape and they don't like it?
如果他们说我很糟?
What if they say I'm no good?
如果他们说: 从这里滚出去 小鬼! 没前途!
What if they say, "Get out of here, kid. You got no future"?
我是说 我不知道 是否受得了这样的拒绝
I mean, I just don't think I can take that kind of rejection.
天哪 我像极了我的父亲
Jesus, I'm starting to sound like my old man.
- 得了 他还不算太遭 - 救救钟楼!
- Come on. He's not that bad. - Save the clock tower.
至少他给你买了辆车
At least he's letting you borrow the car tomorrow night.
看 四轮驱动
Check out that 4x4.
真棒!
That is hot.
停在这
Okay. Back her up.
总有一天 詹尼弗 总有一天
Someday, Jennifer. Someday.
开着这车到湖边 不是很棒吗?
Wouldn't it be great to take that truck up to the lake?
钻进车后的睡袋里
Throw a couple of sleeping bags in the back.
看着繁星在上...
Lie out underneath the stars.
- 停下 - 怎么了?
- Stop it. - What?
你妈妈知道吗 明晚的事?
Does your mom know? About tomorrow night?
出镇的事吗?
No, get out of town.
她还以为我是和那帮朋友露营
My mom thinks I'm going camping with the guys.
詹尼弗 如果她知道我和你在一起
Jennifer, my mother would freak out
她会疯掉的!
if she knew I was going up there with you,
她总是一本正经的说
and I'd get the standard lecture about
她当年从没做过这种无聊的事情
how she never did that kind of stuff when she was a kid.
我是说 她生来就是个修女
I mean, look, I think the woman was born a nun.
我认为她只是想 让你保持举止端正
She's just trying to keep you respectable.
是吗 那么她做得并不成功
Well, she's not doing a very good job.
是糟透了
Terrible.
救救钟楼! 救救钟楼!
Save the clock tower. Save the clock tower.
威尔逊市长提出议案 欲更换那个钟
Mayor Wilson is sponsoring an initiative to replace that clock.
30年前 闪电击中钟楼
Thirty years ago, lightning struck that clock tower
从此钟楼停摆了
and the clock hasn't run since.
我们山谷镇文物保护协会认为
We at the Hill Valley Preservation Society
应该完整的保留下来
think it should be preserved exactly the way it is
它是我们历史和传统的一部分
as part of our history and heritage.
给你 女士 25美分
There you go, lady. There's a quarter.
谢谢
Thank you.
别忘了拿份传单
Don't forget to take a flyer.
好的
Right.
救救钟楼!
Save the clock tower!
我们说到哪了?
Where were we?
就说到这
Right about here.
詹尼弗!
Jennifer!
是我爸爸 我得走了
It's my dad. I've got to go. Right.
今晚给你电话
I'll call you tonight.
我要去祖母家
I'll be at my grandma's.
给你电话号码
Here, let me give you the number.
再见
Bye.
(我爱你!)
(里昂住宅区)
BTD 6-2-9
Bravo, Tango, Delta 6-2-9.
需要拖车 收到的单位快回复
Tow for impoundment. Any unit, please respond.
好极了 真是太好了
Perfect. Just perfect.
真不能相信你竟然
I can't believe you'd loan me your car
借给我一辆有问题的车
without telling me it had a blind spot.
想要我被撞死吗?
Blind spot? I could've been killed.
贝夫 听着
Now, Biff, now, I never noticed
此前我开车的时候 从没见到有什么问题
that the car had any blind spot before when I would drive it.
嗨 儿子
Hi, Son.
你瞎了眼了 麦佛莱? 就在那儿!
What, are you blind, McFly? It's there.
外面那堆废铁你怎么解释?
How else do you explain that wreck out there?
贝夫 我能说个请求吗?
Biff, can I assume
该拿...你的保险金 来赔偿车子的损坏
that your insurance is going to pay for the damage?
我的保险金? 这可是你的车!
My insurance? It's your car.
你自己赔去吧!
Your insurance should pay for it.
我只想知道谁来赔偿这个?
I wanna know who's going to pay for this?
出事时 车子把酒洒我到衣服上了
I spilled beer all over it when the car smashed into me.
谁来付我的清洗帐单呢?
Who's gonna pay my cleaning bill?
我的报告在哪?
And where's my reports?
我还没做完
Well, I haven't finished those up yet,
但你知道 我正在做...
but I figured since they weren't due till...
喂 喂 有人在家吗?
Hello? Hello? Anybody home? Huh?
想一想! 麦佛莱! 想一想!
Think, McFly. Think! All right.
我还得花时间重新打字呢
I got to have time to get them retyped.
如果我直接将你的手写报告交上去
Do you realize what would happen
你知道会发生什么吗?
if I hand in my reports in your handwriting?
我会被开除的
I'll get fired.
你不想让这样的事情发生吧?
You wouldn't want that to happen, would you?
- 是吧? - 当然 贝夫
- Would you? - Of course not, Biff.
我不希望这样的事情发生
Now, I wouldn't want that to happen.
我今晚就完成报告
Now, look. I'll finish those reports on up tonight,
明天一大早就给你送去 好吗?
and I'll run them on over first thing tomorrow, all right?
别太早了 星期六我睡懒觉
Not too early. I sleep in Saturday.
看 你鞋带松了
McFly, your shoe's untied.
别犯傻了 麦佛莱
Don't be so gullible, McFly.
把撞坏的地方修好 麦佛莱
Got the place fixed up nice, though, McFly.
我大老远把车给你拖来
I have your car towed all the way to your house
就给我喝这么淡的酒吗?
and all you got for me is lite beer?
看什么看 呆小子?
What are you looking at, butthead?
代我向你妈问好
Say hi to your mom for me.
我知道你要说什么 孩子
I know what you're going to say, Son,
你是对的 没错
and you're right. You're right.
但贝夫是我的主管
But Biff just happens to be my supervisor,
而我我不善应对
And I'm afraid I'm just not very good at confrontations.
这车子 爸爸
But the car, Dad.
我意思是 他弄坏了车 就得为此负责
I mean, he wrecked it. He totaled it.
我非常需要这车 爸爸
I needed that car tomorrow night, Dad.
你不知道这车对我有多重要
Do you have any idea how important this was to me?
明白吗?
Do you have any clue?
我知道 但我只能说...
I know, and all I can say is, I'm...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
相信我 马丁
Believe me, Marty, you're better off
别为这些事情头疼
without having to worry about all the aggravation
伤脑筋
and headaches of playing at that dance.
你说的很对
He's absolutely right, Marty.
别为那些事伤脑筋
The last thing you need is headaches.
孩子们 这蛋糕我们得自己吃了
Kids, we're going to have to eat this cake by ourselves.
乔伊叔叔的假释又没通过
Your Uncle Joey didn't make parole again.
(欢迎乔伊叔叔回来!)
你们最好给他写封信
I think it would be nice if you all dropped him a line.
那个"囚鸟叔叔"乔伊吗?
Uncle "Jailbird" Joey?
他到底是不是你弟弟呀 妈妈?
He's your brother, Mom.
有个蹲监狱的叔叔 真是奇耻大辱
Yeah. I think it's a major embarrassment, having an uncle in prison.
我们一生中都会犯错 孩子们
We all make mistakes in life, children.
该死 我要迟到了
God damn it. I'm late.
大卫 管好你的嘴!
David, watch your mouth!
到这来 走之前亲亲你的妈妈
You come here and kiss your mother before you go. Come here.
妈妈 快点 我要错过巴士了
Come on, Mom. Make it fast. I'll miss my bus.
再见 爸爸
See you later, Pop.
该换发油了
Time to change that oil.
嘿 马丁 我可不是你的电话答复员
Hey, Marty. I'm not your answering service.
刚才你在外头 为车子伤脑筋那阵子
While you were outside pouting over the car,
詹妮弗·帕克给你打了两次电话
Jennifer Parker called you twice.
我不喜欢她 马丁
I don't like her, Marty.
打电话给男孩的女孩只会惹麻烦
Any girl who calls up a boy is just asking for trouble.
妈妈 女孩打电话给男孩没什么错
Oh, Mother, there's nothing wrong with calling a boy.
我认为这糟透了 女孩追男孩
I think it's terrible. Girls chasing boys.
我在你这年纪 从没追过男孩 打电话给男孩
When I was your age, I never chased a boy or called a boy
和男孩坐在车里
or sat in a parked car with a boy.
妈妈 那我怎么找对象啊?
Then how am I supposed to ever meet anybody?
你会遇到的
Well, it'll just happen.
就像我遇见你们的父亲一样
Like the way I met your father.
那样太傻了 是外公的车子撞到了他
That was so stupid. Grandpa hit him with the car.
那是命中注定
It was meant to be.
如果外公没撞倒他
Anyway, if Grandpa hadn't hit him,
就不会有你们几个了
then none of you would have been born.
是吗
Yeah, well.
真不知道 那时老爸
I still don't understand what Dad was doing
在路中间干什么
in the middle of the street.
你那时在干什么 乔治? 看鸟吗?
What was it, George? Bird-watching?
什么 洛莲?
What, Lorraine? What?
不管怎样 你们外公的车把他撞倒了
Anyway, your Grandpa hit him with the car
把他带到房里
and brought him into the house.
他看起来是那样的无助
He seemed so helpless,
就像一只迷路的小狗 我的心就这样被他带走了
like a little lost puppy, and my heart just went out to him.
妈妈 这故事你讲了无数次了
Yeah, Mom, we know. You've told us this story a million times.
你觉得很对不起他
You felt sorry for him,
于是你决定和他一起走
so you decided to go with him
去那个"海里之鱼舞会"
to the Fish Under the Sea dance.
不 是"海中魅力舞会"
No. It was the Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
我们的第一次约会 我永生不忘
Our first date. I'll never forget it.
就在暴风雨的那个晚上 还记得吗 乔治?
It was the night of that terrible thunderstorm, remember, George?
你们父亲在舞池里第一次吻了我
Your father kissed me for the very first time on that dance floor.
就在那一刻我明白了
It was then that I realized
我余下的生命时光 将要和他一同度过
that I was going to spend the rest of my life with him.
你好
Hello.
马丁 你没睡着吧?
Marty, you didn't fall asleep, did you?
博士
Doc.
没有 博士 没有 别傻了
No. No, don't be silly.
听着 这很重要 我忘了拿摄像机
Listen, this is very important. I forgot my video camera.
你能否在来购物超市之前 到我那去拿吗?
Can you stop by my place and pick it up on your way to the mall?
可以 我这就去
Yeah. I'm on my way.
(双松购物超市)
(布朗博士公司)
爱因斯坦 博士在那里呢? 你知道吗?
Einstein! Hey, Einstein, where's the doc, boy? Huh?
博士!
Doc!
马丁 你终于来了!
Marty! You made it!
是啊
Yeah.
欢迎来到我的最新试验 这是个大试验
Welcome to my latest experiment. This is the big one,
我一生的时间都在等待它
the one I've been waiting for all my life.
这是怎么回事...
Well, it's a DeLorean...
稍安勿躁 你会知道的
Bear with me, Marty. All your questions will be answered.
装上磁带
Roll tape and we'll proceed.
博士
Doc,
你就这样穿吗?
is that a DEVO suit?
不管了 不管了
Never mind that now.
不管了
Not now.
我准备好了
All right. I'm ready.
晚上好 我是 埃米特·布朗博士
Good evening. I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
我正站在双松购物超市停车场
I'm standing on the parking lot at Twin Pines Mall.
现在是1985年10月26日 凌晨1点18分
It's Saturday morning, October 26, 1985, 1:18 a.m.,
这是1号临时试验
and this is temporal experiment number one.
来吧 爱因斯坦 到那儿去
Come on, Einie. Hey, hey, boy, get in there.
乖孩子 坐好
That a boy! In you go. Sit down.
系好安全带 就这样
Put your seat belt on. That's it.
好的
Okay.
请注意爱因斯坦的钟
Please note that Einstein's clock
时间和我的完全同步
is in precise synchronization with my control watch.
没错
Got it? Right. Check, Doc.
对上了
Good.
旅途愉快 爱因斯坦 小心你的头
Have a good trip, Einstein. Watch your head.
这东西能遥控车子吗?
You got that thing hooked up to the car?
注意看
Watch this.
好的
Yeah. Okay. Got it.
天啊!
Jesus!
别拍我! 拍车子!
Not me! The car! The car!
如果我计算正确
If my calculations are correct,
当时速达到88英里时
when this baby hits 88 miles per hour
会有惊人的事情发生
you're going to see some serious shit.
看好了 看好了
Watch this. Watch this.
我怎么跟你说的了?
What did I tell you?
时速88英里!
88 miles per hour!
车子消失了
The temporal displacement occurred
正好是在 1:20 零秒!
exactly 1:20 a.m. And zero seconds!
我的老天!
Jesus Christ!
天啊 博士 你把爱因斯坦分解了!
Jesus Christ, Doc! You disintegrated Einstein!
镇定 马丁 我可没分解任何东西
Calm down, Marty. I didn't disintegrate anything.
它在车里完好如初
The molecular structure of both Einstein and the car are completely intact.
可它们到底在哪?
Then where the hell are they?
恰当的问法是:
The appropriate question is,
"它们到底在什么时间?"
"When the hell are they?"
知道吗 爱因斯坦成为了世界上第一个时间旅行者!
You see, Einstein has just become the world's first time traveler.
我把它送到了未来!
I sent him into the future.
正好是未来的1分钟
One minute into the future, to be exact.
当正好到1:21 零秒
At precisely 1:21 a.m. And zero seconds,
我们就会在那时间机器里找到它
we shall catch up with him and the time machine.
等一等 等一等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, Doc.
博士 你是说 你把一台时间机器
Are you telling me that you built a time machine
装在了那高级跑车里?
out of a DeLorean?
我要说呢
The way I see it,
既然要把时间机器造在车里
if you're going to build a time machine into a car,
为何不摩登一些呢?
why not do it with some style?
而且这样的结构很有帮助...
Besides, the stainless-steel construction made the flux dispersal...
当心!
Look out!
怎么了? 很烫?
What? Is it hot?
很冷 冷极了
It's cold. Damn cold.
爱因斯坦! 小家伙!
Einstein, you little devil!
爱因斯坦的表 正好比我的
Einstein's clock is exactly one minute
慢了1分钟!
behind mine and still ticking!
- 它没事? - 它好得很
- He's all right. - He's fine.
它什么都不会感觉到
And he's completely unaware that anything happened.
对它而言这是瞬间完成的
As far as he's concerned, the trip was instantaneous.
这就是为什么它的钟比我的慢1分钟
That's why his watch is exactly one minute behind mine.
它完全跳过了那一分钟
He skipped over that minute
瞬间到达现在
to instantly arrive at this moment in time.
过来 让你看看如何操作
Come here. I'll show you how it works.
好的
All right.
首先 把时间电路打开
First, you turn the time circuits on.
这个显示"将来"要去的时间
This readout tells you where you're going.
这个显示"现在"所在的时间
This one tells you where you are.
这个显示"原来"所在的时间
This one tells you where you were.
用这个键盘输入你的目标时间
You input your destination time on this keypad.
比如 你想去见证
Say you want to see the signing
独立宣言的签署
of the Declaration of Independence.
或者去看看耶稣的诞生
Or witness the birth of Christ.
或是这个 科学的重要历史时刻
Here's a red-letter date in the history of science.
1955年11月5日
November 5th, 1955.
是啊 当然 1955年11月5日
Yes, of course. November 5th, 1955.
那天发生什么事了?
What? I don't get it. What happened?
那是我发明时间旅行的日子 我记得很清楚
That was the day I invented time travel. I remember it vividly.
那天我正站在马桶上要挂钟
I was standing on the edge of my toilet, hanging a clock.
地板很湿 我滑倒了
The porcelain was wet. I slipped,
脑袋撞在水池边上
hit my head on the edge of the sink,
当舒醒的时候 我看到了启示
and when I came to, I had a revelation,
一个幻影 一张图片 呈现于我脑中 就是这个东西
a vision, a picture in my head, a picture of this.
就是它 使时间旅行成为可能 通量电容器
This is what makes time travel possible. The flux capacitor.
什么电容器?
Flux capacitor?
我耗费了30年时间 用尽所有家产
It's taken me almost 30 years and my entire family fortune
去实现那天的幻影
to realize the vision of that day.
我的天 多么长的时间啊?
My God, has it been that long?
这里一切都变了
Things have certainly changed around here.
我记得当时这里是
I remember when this was all farmland
一望无际的农田
as far as the eye could see.
全都是一个皮博迪的老头的
Old man Peabody owned all of this.
他有个疯狂的念头 繁殖松树
He had this crazy idea about breeding pine trees.
这真是个...重要的日子 博士 棒极了
This is heavy-duty, Doc. This is great.
它用的是普通的无铅汽油吗?
Does it run on regular unleaded gasoline?
很不幸 不是 它需要
Unfortunately, no. It requires something
更大的功力 它用钚!
with a little more kick. Plutonium.
钚? 等一等
Plutonium. Wait a minute.
你是说 这东西是核能驱动的?
Are you telling me that this sucker is nuclear?
嘿! 嘿! 继续拍
Hey, hey, hey! Keep rolling. Keep rolling there.
不 不! 它用电驱动
No, no, no, this sucker's electrical,
但只有核反应
but I need a nuclear reaction
才能产生所需的1.21兆瓦电能
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts of electricity I need.
博士 你不可能在商店里买到钚
Doc, you don't just walk into a store and buy plutonium.
是你偷来的吗?
Did you rip that off?
当然不是 我从利比亚民族分子那里弄到的
Of course. From a group of Libyan nationalists.
他们要我造炸弹
They wanted me to build them a bomb,
我拿走了他们的钚 留下一个
so I took their plutonium and, in turn, gave them a shoddy bomb casing
玩具零件做的假弹
full of used pinball machine parts.
- 过来 准备添加钚燃料... - 天哪!
- Come on. Let's get you a radiation suit. - Jesus!
准备加料
We must prepare to reload.
现在安全了 脱下面罩
It's safe now. Everything's lead-lined.
别把录像带弄丢了
Don't you lose those tapes now.
我需要它
I need that as a record.
放在这里 好了
Let's put this back here. There we go.
忘了拿行李
I almost forgot my luggage.
谁知道未来有没有棉衣?
Who knows if they've got cotton underwear in the future?
我对合成材料过敏
I'm allergic to all synthetics.
未来?
The future?
那么你要去哪?
That's where you're going?
25年后的未来
That's right, 25 years into the future.
我一直梦想看到人类未来 开开眼界
I've always dreamed of seeing the future, looking beyond my years,
看看人类的进步
seeing the progress of mankind.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
我也能看到25年后 世界球赛的获胜队
I'll also be able to see who wins the next 25 World Series.
博士
Doc.
干嘛?
Huh?
到那之后 别忘了看看我
Look me up when you get there.
会的 录像
Indeed, I will. Roll 'em.
我 埃米特·布朗博士
I, Dr. Emmett Brown,
将开始一次历史性的旅行
am about to embark on an historic journey.
我在想什么啊?
What am I thinking of?
我差点忘了带额外的钚
I almost forgot to bring extra plutonium.
我可怎么回来啊? 一份钚 一次旅行
How did I ever expect to get back? One pellet, one trip.
我一定是昏了头了 对不对?
I must be out of my mind.
怎么了 宝贝?
What is it, Einie?
天哪!
Oh, my God.
他们找到我了! 真不知他们是怎么找到我的?
They found me. I don't know how, but they found me.
快跑 马丁!
Run for it, Marty!
谁? 谁?
Who? Who?
你以为是谁? 是那些利比亚人!
Who do you think? The Libyans!
糟了!
Holy shit!
我来还击!
I'll draw their fire!
博士 等等!
Doc, wait!
不!
No!
混蛋!
You bastard!
追! 俄罗斯的垃圾枪
Go! Damn Soviet gun.
追!
Go!
快呀! 快呀! 见鬼!
Come on! Move, damn it!
天啊!
Jesus!
真要命!
Holy shit!
看你能不能加速到90英里
Let's see if you bastards can do 90.
那是什么 保罗?
What is it? What is it, Pa?
像是飞机 但怎么没翅膀?
Looks like an airplane without wings.
爸爸 它不是飞机 你看!
That ain't no airplane. Look.
(太空传奇  来自冥王星的僵尸)
快跑!
Children!
听我说...
Listen... Whoa.
喂?
Hello?
对不起
Excuse me.
很抱歉弄坏了谷仓
Sorry about your barn.
它变成人样了! 快开枪!
It's already mutated into human form! Shoot it!
滚开! 你这个外星杂种!
Take that, you mutated son of a bitch!
让开!
Get away!
停下
Hold it.
快开枪!
Shoot it, Pa!
杂种! ..."皮博迪"
My pine! Why you...
外星杂种 你弄死了我的松树!
You space bastard! You killed our pine!
(双松种植场)
好了 麦佛莱 麦佛莱
All right. All right. Okay, McFly.
醒醒 这只是场梦
Get a grip on yourself. It's all a dream.
一场非常刺激的梦
It's just a very intense dream.
(里昂住宅区)
(欢迎入住 里昂住宅区)
听着 你们得帮帮我...
Listen, you got to help me.
别停下! 他会杀了我们的!
Don't stop, Wilbur! Don't!
不可能
It can't be.
真是疯了
This is nuts.
快发动
Come on.
好极了
Perfect.
(钚燃料箱: 空)
(山谷镇  2英里)
(欢迎来到 山谷镇)
别忘了 前途就在你们手中
Remember, fellow citizens, the future is in your hands.
如果你们想要进步 请投 托马斯 一票
If you believe in progress, re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
他代表着进步
Progress is his middle name.
雷德·托马斯 市长的政见就是
Mayor Red Thomas' progress platform
更多的工作 更好的教育
means more jobs, better education,
更多人权 更少税收
bigger civic improvements and lower taxes.
选举之日 投票给众望所归的领袖
On election day, cast your vote for a proven leader.
雷德·托马斯 连任市长
Re-elect Mayor Red Thomas.
(1955年11月5日)
这准是场梦
This has got to be a dream.
(公用电话)
年轻人 你干什么了? 刚跳船吗?
Hey, kid. What'd you do? Jump ship?
怎么了?
What?
为什么穿着救生衣?
What's with the life preserver?
我要用电话机
I just want to use the phone.
在后面
Yeah, it's in the back.
埃米特
Brown.
是你 没错了
Great. You're alive.
快接电话
Come on.
你知道河滨路 1640号在哪里吗
Do you know where 1640 Riverside...
要点什么 年轻人?
Are you going to order something, kid?
给我一杯"啤酒"(现代俚语)
Yeah. Give me a Tab.
水龙头(与"啤酒"同音)? 那可不行 你要些别的东西
Tab? I can't give you a tab unless you order something.
给我杯"百事"可乐
Right. Give me a Pepsi Free.
想要付帐单(与"百事"同音) 你得先要些东西
You want a Pepsi, pal, you're going to pay for it.
就给我些不加糖的饮料好了
Just give me something without any sugar in it, okay?
不加糖的饮料
Something without sugar.
嘿 麦佛莱!
Hey, McFly.
你以为你在干什么呢?
What do you think you're doing?
贝夫
Biff.
我在和你说话呢 你这个爱尔兰臭虫!
I'm talking to you, McFly, you Irish bug!
嘿 贝夫! 伙计们 你们怎么在这儿?
Hey, Biff. Hey, guys. How are you doing?
我的作业做完了吗? 麦佛莱?
You got my homework finished, McFly?
哦 实际上我忘了 星期一才交 所以...
Well, actually, I figured since it wasn't due till Monday...
喂? 喂? 有人在家吗?
Hello? Hello? Anybody home?
想一想! 麦佛莱! 想一想!
Think, McFly. Think! Okay.
我还得花时间抄呢
I got to have time to recopy it.
如果我交上有你笔迹的作业
You realize what would happen
你知道会发生什么吗?
if I hand in my homework in your handwriting?
我会被踢出学校
I'll get kicked out of school.
你不想让这样的事情发生吧?
You wouldn't want that to happen, would you?
不是吗?
Would you?
当然不会
Now, of course not, Biff.
我不希望这样的事情发生
No. I wouldn't want that to happen.
看什么看 呆小子!
What are you looking at, butthead?
看那 贝夫! 他穿着救生衣
Biff, get a load of this guy's life preserver.
他以为会被淹死
Dork thinks he's going to drown.
我的作业怎么办 麦佛莱?
How about my homework, McFly?
好吧 贝夫 我今晚就完成报告
Okay, Biff. Well, I'll finish that on up tonight
明天一大早就给你送去
and then I'll bring it over first thing tomorrow morning.
别太早 星期天我睡懒觉
Not too early. I sleep in Sundays.
麦佛莱 你鞋带松了!
Oh, McFly, your shoe's untied!
别犯傻了 麦佛莱
Don't be so gullible, McFly. Okay.
我不想在这再看到你!
I don't want to see you in here again.
好的 再见
Okay. All right. Bye-bye.
怎么了?
What?
你是 乔治·麦佛莱?
You're George McFly.
对 你是谁?
Yeah. Who are you?
懒散的家伙 你怎么能
Say! Why do you let those boys
让他们这样耍你?
push you around like that for?
他们块头比我大
Well, they're bigger than me.
要有骨气 你得自重些
Stand tall, boy. Have some respect for yourself.
你不知道 他们现在这样利用你
Don't you know, if you let people walk over you now,
以后会利用你一辈子
they'll be walking over you for the rest of your life.
看看我 你以为
Look at me. You think I'm gonna
我会在这个小店里呆一辈子吗?
spend the rest of my life in this slop house?
- 说话小心点 - 不 先生
- Watch it, Goldie. - No, sir!
我要干大事
I'm gonna make something of myself.
我在上夜校
I'm going to night school,
总有一天我要当上大人物
and one day, I'm going to be somebody.
没错 他会当上市长
That's right. He's going to be mayor.
是的...
Yeah, I'm...
市长?
Mayor!
这是个好主意 我可以竞选市长
Now that's a good idea! I could run for mayor.
黑人市长? 真是个奇迹
A colored mayor. That'll be the day.
你等着 我会当上市长的
You wait and see, Mr. Caruthers. I will be mayor.
我要成为山谷镇最有势力的人
I'll be the most powerful man in Hill Valley,
我要好好清理这个镇子
and I'm going to clean up this town.
好啊 你先从清理地板开始
Good. You can start by sweeping the floor.
威尔逊市长 我喜欢听到这句话!
Mayor Goldie Wilson. I like the sound of that.
该死!
Shit
爸爸...乔治 你还有自行车!
Hey, Dad! George! Hey, you on the bike!
他是个偷窥狂!
He's a peeping Tom.
爸爸!
Dad!
等等 你是谁?
Hey, wait a minute. Wait a minute. Who are you?
斯塔拉! 我的车又撞倒了
Stella! Another one of these damn kids
一个呆小子!
jumped in front of my car!
过来帮忙把他抬到房子里
Come on out here! Help me take him in the house!
妈妈 是你吗?
Mom? That you?
你醒了 放松点
There, there, now. Just relax.
你几乎睡了9个小时
You've been asleep for almost nine hours now.
真是场恶梦
I had a horrible nightmare.
还好及时回来了 真可怕
I dreamed that I went back in time. It was terrible.
那么
Well,
欢迎回到美好的1955年
you're safe and sound now, back in good old 1955.
1955年?
1955?
你是我妈妈 你是我妈妈!
You're my... You're my...
我名叫洛莲
My name is Lorraine.
洛莲·贝恩斯
Lorraine Baines.
没错!
Yeah.
但你..你真是太...
But you're... You're so...
太苗条了!
You're so thin!
放松 卡尔文 你的头撞伤了
Just relax, Calvin. You got a big bruise on your head.
我裤子呢?
Where are my pants?
在那 在我的衣箱上
Over there, on my hope chest.
我还没见过紫色的内裤 卡尔文
I've never seen purple underwear before, Calvin.
卡尔文? 为什么你一直叫我卡尔文?
Calvin? Why do you keep calling me Calvin?
这不是你的名字吗? 卡尔文·克雷恩?(内裤品牌名)
Well, that is your name, isn't it? Calvin Klein?
你内裤上写得到处都是
It's written all over your underwear.
大家是不是叫你 卡尔?
Oh, I guess they call you Cal, huh?
不 实际上 大家叫我马丁
No, actually, people call me Marty.
很高兴见到你 卡尔文...
Pleased to meet you, Calvin.
马丁
Marty.
克雷恩
Klein.
你介意我坐在这吗?
Do you mind if I sit here?
不 很好
No. Fine.
不 很好 很好
No. Good. Fine. Good.
你的伤口不小呢
That's a big bruise you have there.
洛莲 亲爱的你还好吗?
Lorraine, are you up there?
上帝 我妈妈!
Oh, my God! It's my mother!
快穿上你的牛仔裤!
Quick! Put your pants back on!
马丁 你来这多久了?
So, tell me, Marty, how long have you been in port?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
看你穿着救生衣
I guessed you're a sailor.
准是个水手
That's why you wear that life preserver.
是海岸防卫队吗?
Coast Guard.
山姆 他就是
Sam, here's the young man
你撞到的那个年轻人
you hit with your car out there.
他很好 感谢上帝
He's all right. Thank God.
你这年纪在路中间干什么?
What were you doing in the middle of the street, a kid your age?
别太在意 他心情不好
Don't pay attention to him. He's in one of his moods.
山姆 别弄那东西了
Sam, you quit fiddling with that thing.
过来吃晚餐
Come in here to dinner.
我来介绍 你已见过洛莲了
Now, let's see. You already know Lorraine.
这是内利森 这是萨利 那是托比
This is Milton, this is Sally, that's Toby,
在娃娃床里的是乔伊
and over there in the playpen is little baby Joey.
原来你就是我的乔伊舅舅
So, you're my uncle Joey.
这铁窗你最好习惯点
Better get used to these bars, kid.
是呀! 乔伊就是喜欢呆在娃娃床里
Yes. Joey just loves being in his playpen.
只要把他带出来他就哭
He cries whenever we take him out,
所以我们整天都把他放在里面
so we just leave him in there all the time.
马丁 但愿你喜欢吃肉丸子
Well, Marty, I hope you like meatloaf.
听我说 我只是...
Listen, I really ought to...
坐这 马丁
Sit here, Marty.
山姆 别弄那东西了
Sam, stop fiddling with that thing
过来吃晚餐
and come in here and eat your dinner.
看那! 可以用了!
Look at it roll.
我们可以一边吃饭一边看电视了
Now we can watch Jackie Gleason while we eat.
我们家的第一台电视机
It's our first television set.
爸爸今天挑的
Dad just picked it up today.
你有电视机吗?
Do you have a television?
当然 我们家有两台
Well, yeah. You know we have two of them.
你一定很有钱!
Wow! You must be rich.
宝贝 他是逗你的
Oh, honey, he's teasing you.
没人有两台电视机
Nobody has two television sets.
这个我看过
Hey. Hey, I've seen this one.
我看过! 这是个老家节目了!
I've seen this one! This is a classic.
那个人穿得像个太空人
This is where Ralph dresses up as a man from space.
"看过"是什么意思? 这可是最新的
What do you mean, you've seen this? It's brand-new.
我曾经看过...它的重播
Yeah, well, I saw it on a rerun.
什么是"重播"?
What's a rerun?
你会知道的
You'll find out.
知道吗 马丁 你看起来很面熟 我认识你的母亲吗?
You know, Marty, you look so familiar to me. Do I know your mother?
是的 我想你认识
Yeah, I think maybe you do.
哦 我想给她打个电话
Oh, then I want to give her a call.
我不想让她担心你
I don't want her to worry about you.
不行
You can't.
现在家里没人
That is, nobody's home.
是的
Yet.
你知道河滨路在哪吗?
Listen, do you know where Riverside Drive is?
在小镇另一边
It's on the other end of town.
梅伯路的后面 小镇的东边
A block past Maple. East end of town.
等等 梅伯路后面
Wait a minute, a block past Maple.
那是约翰·肯尼迪路
That's John F. Kennedy Drive.
谁是约翰·肯尼迪?
Who the hell is John F. Kennedy?
妈妈
Mother?
也许马丁的父母出镇去了
With Marty's parents out of town,
你不认为该留他过夜吗?
don't you think he ought to spend the night?
毕竟 爸爸差点把他撞死
I mean, after all, Dad almost killed him with the car.
那倒是 马丁
That's true, Marty.
你该留下来过夜
I think maybe you should spend the night.
这是我们的责任
I think you're our responsibility.
啊 不必了
Gee, I don't know.
他可以睡在我的房间里
And he can sleep in my room.
我得走了 我得走了
I gotta go! I gotta go!
谢谢你们 晚餐很不错
Thanks very much. It was wonderful.
你们人也不错 以后见 不会等太久的
You were all great. See you all later. Much later.
他是个奇怪的年轻人
He's a very strange young man.
他是个白痴
He's an idiot.
家庭教养有问题 他父母一定也是白痴
Comes from upbringing. His parents are probably idiots, too.
洛莲 如果你有这样的孩子
Lorraine, you ever have a kid
我就和你断绝关系
who acts that way, I'll disown you.
博士?
Doc?
别说话
Don't say a word.
我不想知道你的名字
I don't wanna know your name.
我不想知道你的任何东西
I don't want to know anything about you.
- 听着 博士 - 别说话!
- Listen, Doc... - Quiet!
- 博士 是我 马丁 - 什么也别说
- Doc, it's me, Marty. - Don't tell me anything.
- 博士 你要帮我... - 别说话! 别说话!
- Doc, you got to help... - Quiet. Quiet.
我要读出你的思想
I'm going to read your thoughts.
你从很远的地方来?
Let's see now. You've come here from a great distance?
对了!
Yeah. Exactly.
别告诉我!
Don't tell me!
你要我订
You want me to buy a subscription
周六晚报
to the Saturday Evening Post.
不对
No.
别说话! 别说话!
Not a word. Not a word now!
安静
Quiet.
是捐款 你要我捐款
Donations. You want me to make a donation
给海岸防卫队的补给舰
to the Coast Guard Youth Auxiliary.
博士
Doc.
我来自未来
I'm from the future.
我乘坐你发明的时间机器来的
I came here in a time machine that you invented.
我需要你帮助我回到1985年
Now, I need your help to get back to the year 1985.
天哪
My God.
你知道这意味着什么吗?
Do you know what this means?
这意味着这狗东西 一点用也没有!
It means that this damn thing doesn't work at all!
你得帮助我 你是唯一
Doc, you got to help me. You are the only one
知道时间机器如何工作的人
who knows how your time machine works.
时间机器 我可没发明过什么时间机器
Time machine? I haven't invented any time machine.
好吧 我证明给你看
Okay. All right, I'll prove it to you.
我的驾照 1987年到期
Look at my driver's license. Expires 1987.
看我的生日 会令你大吃一惊!
Look at my birthday, for crying out loud!
我还没出生呢
I haven't even been born yet.
看这照片
And look at this picture.
我哥哥 我姐姐 还有我
It's my brother, my sister and me.
看运动衫 1984年的
Look at her sweatshirt, Doc. "Class of 1984"?
这照片真糟糕
Pretty mediocre photographic fakery.
你哥哥的脑袋被截去了一半
They cut off your brother's hair.
我说的是实话 博士 你得相信我
I'm telling the truth, Doc. You got to believe me.
那告诉我 你这未来小子
Then tell me, future boy,
1985年美国总统是谁?
Who's President of the United States in 1985?
洛伦·里根(曾经当过演员)
Ronald Reagan.
洛伦·里根 那个三流演员?
Ronald Reagan? The actor?
那副总统是谁? 杰瑞·李维斯吗?
Then who's vice president? Jerry Lewis?
珍妮·怀曼 是第一夫人
I suppose Jane Wyman is the First Lady.
等等 博士!
Whoa. Wait, Doc!
泰德·克班尼 就是财政部部长
And Jack Benny is secretary of the treasury.
博士 你得听我说!
Doc, you gotta listen to me.
我今天够忙的了
I've had enough practical jokes for one evening.
再见 祝你好运 未来小子!
Good night, future boy!
等等 博士
No, wait, Doc. Doc.
撞伤 你头部的撞伤 我知道是怎么回事
The bruise on your head, I know how that happened.
你全告诉了我
You told me the whole story.
你站在马桶上
You were standing on your toilet
准备挂钟
and you were hanging a clock,
你滑倒了 撞在水池上
and you fell and you hit your head on the sink.
一个念头忽现: 通量电容器
That's when you came up with the idea for the flux capacitor,
就是它 使时间旅行成为可能
which is what makes time travel possible.
它发动不起来 所以我把它藏在这
There's something wrong with the starter, so I hid it here.
在厕所摔倒之后 我画了这个
After I fell off my toilet, I drew this.
通量电容器
The flux capacitor.
成功了!
It works!
我终于发明了能用的东西!
I finally invent something that works!
它当然可以用
You bet your ass it works.
我们得把它偷偷弄回实验室
Somehow we've got to sneak this back to my laboratory.
我们着手把你送回家吧!
We've got to get you home!
博士 就是这
Okay, Doc, this is it.
不管了 不管了
Never mind that. Never mind that now.
看呀! 是我! 我变成老头了!
Why, that's me! Look at me! I'm an old man.
晚上好 我是 埃米特·布朗博士
Good evening. I'm Dr. Emmett Brown.
我正站在双松购物超市停车场
I'm standing on the parking lot at Twin Pines Mall.
感谢上帝 我还有头发
Thank God, I've still got my hair.
我穿着什么?
What's on Earth is this thing I'm wearing?
那是防辐射衣
This is a radiation suit.
防辐射衣?
Radiation suit?
是啊! 就跟原子沉落一样
Of course. 'Cause of all the fallout from the atomic wars.
这 真是了不起
This is truly amazing.
一个手提电视摄像机
A portable television studio.
难怪你们的总统是个演员
No wonder your president has to be an actor.
因为他在电视上好看些
He's gotta look good on television.
到了 就是这部分
Whoa. This is it. This is the part coming up, Doc.
这依靠电能
No, no, no, this sucker's electrical,
只有核反应
but I need a nuclear reaction
才能产生所需的 1.21 兆瓦电能...
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts...
我在说什么?
What did I just say?
这依靠电能
This sucker's electrical,
只有核反应
but I need a nuclear reaction
才能产生所需的 1.21 兆瓦电能...
to generate the 1.21 gigawatts...
1.21 兆瓦!
1.21 gigawatts!
1.21 gigawatts.
我的天!
Great Scott!
"兆瓦特"是什么?
What the hell is a gigawatt?
我怎么会如此随便? 1.21 兆瓦是多少啊?
How could I have been so careless? 1.21 gigawatts!
我怎么弄到如此巨大的能量?
Tom, how am I going to generate that kind of power?
办不到
It can't be done, can it?
博士 博士 我们只需要一点点钚
Doc, look. All we need is a little plutonium.
我知道 在1985年
I'm sure that in 1985,
每个药品商店里都能买到钚
plutonium is available in every corner drugstore,
但在1955年 就很难弄到了
but in 1955, it's a little hard to come by.
马丁 我很抱歉 你被困在这了
Marty, I'm sorry, but I'm afraid you're stuck here.
我不能被困在这 我的生活在1985年
Doc, stuck here? I can't be stuck here. I got a life in 1985.
我还有个女朋友
I got a girl.
她漂亮吗?
Is she pretty?
她非常漂亮 非常爱我
Doc, she's beautiful. She's crazy about me.
看这个 看她在这写的 博士 这说明了一切
Look at this. Look what she wrote here, Doc. I mean, that says it all.
博士 你是我的唯一希望
Doc, you're my only hope.
马丁 对不起 产生1.21兆瓦电能
Marty, I'm sorry, but the only power source capable of generating
的唯一方法 只有闪电
1.21 gigawatts of electricity is a bolt of lightning.
你说什么?
What did you say?
闪电
A bolt of lightning.
不幸的是 你无法知道
Unfortunately, you never know
何时何地会出现闪电
when or where it's ever going to strike.
现在我们知道了
We do now.
就是它! 这就是答案
This is it! This is the answer.
这里写着
It says here that a bolt of lightning
闪电在晚上
is going to strike the clock tower
10:04 击中钟楼 就在下周六晚上!
at precisely 10:04 p.m. Next Saturday night!
如果能设法将闪电
If we could somehow harness this lightning,
导入通量电容器
channel it into the flux capacitor,
就能使它运作
it just might work.
下周六晚我们就能送你回到未来!
Next Saturday night, we're sending you back to the future!
下周六 好极了
Okay, all right. Saturday's good. Saturday's good.
我得在1955年呆上一周了
I can spend a week in 1955.
你带我到处走走吧
I can hang out. You can show me around.
马丁 不行!
Marty, that is completely out of the question.
你必须呆在房子里
You must not leave this house.
你不能见任何人 与任何人说话
You must not see anybody or talk to anybody.
你所做的会对未来有严重影响
Anything you do can have serious repercussions on future events.
明白吗?
Do you understand?
知道了 知道了
Yeah. Sure. Okay.
马丁
Marty,
除我之外 你今天没碰到别人吧?
have you interacted with anybody else today, besides me?
哦 我可能碰到了我的父母
Yeah, well, I might've sort of bumped into my parents.
我的天!
Great Scott!
再看看照片上你的哥哥
Let me see that photograph again of your brother.
正像我说的那样 这验证了我的理论 看你的哥哥
Just as I thought. This proves my theory. Look at your brother.
天啊! 他的头像被擦掉了一样
His head's gone. It's like it's been erased.
擦掉他的存在
Erased from existence.
这地方扫过之后 就像新的一样
They really cleaned this place up. Looks brand-new.
记住
Now remember.
根据我的理论 你干预了
According to my theory, you interfered
你父母的初次相遇
with your parents' first meeting.
没有相遇 他们就不会相爱
If they don't meet, they won't fall in love,
就不会结婚 也就没有孩子
they won't get married and they won't have kids.
因此 你哥哥
That's why your older brother's
从照片上消失了
disappearing from that photograph.
你姐姐是下一个 除非你想办法改变
Your sister will follow, and unless you repair the damage,
否则下一个就是你
you'll be next.
- 听起来非常"严重"(很重) - "很重"? 重量跟这件事无关
- Sounds pretty heavy. - Weight has nothing to do with it.
哪个是你父亲?
Which one's your pop?
就是他
That's him.
好 好 伙计们
Okay. Okay, you guys.
这很有趣 你们真成熟
Very funny. You guys are being real mature.
也许你是被他领养的?
Maybe you were adopted.
你们真成熟
Okay, real mature, guys.
捡起我的书
Okay, pick up my books.
麦佛莱!
McFly.
是 斯特里克兰
That's Strickland.
老天 那家伙长过头发没有?
Jesus, didn't that guy ever have hair?
你这个懒散的家伙
Shape up, man. You're a slacker.
你打算这辈子都这样懒散下去吗?
Do you want to be a slacker for the rest of your life?
不想
No.
你妈妈怎么会看上这样的家伙?
What did your mother ever see in that kid?
我不知道 博士
I don't know, Doc.
我猜我妈妈是
I guess she felt sorry for him
为外公撞倒他而感到抱歉
'cause her dad hit him with the car.
可现在车子撞倒的是我
Hit me with the car.
那是 法伦·史戴伦 效应
That's the Florence Nightingale effect.
医院的护士会爱上病人
It happens in hospitals when nurses fall in love with their patients.
去吧 孩子
Go to it, kid.
乔治 老兄
Hey, George, buddy.
我一直在找你呢
I have been looking all over for you.
还记得我吗? 我救了你命的
You remember me, the guy who saved your life the other day?
- 当然 - 很好
- Yeah. - Good.
我让你见个人
There's somebody I'd like you to meet.
洛莲?
Lorraine?
卡尔文!
Calvin!
见见我的好友 乔治·麦佛莱
I'd like you to meet my good friend George McFly.
嗨 很高兴认识你
Hi. It's really a pleasure to meet you.
你的头怎样了?
How's your head?
很好 没事
Good. Fine.
昨晚你离开之后
Oh. I've been so worried about you
我一直为你担心
ever since you ran off the other night.
- 你还好吗?  - 没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
抱歉我得走了
I'm sorry. I have to go.
走啦!
Come on!
他真是个白马王子
Isn't he a dreamboat?
博士 她对他不屑一顾
Doc, she didn't even look at him.
很糟糕
This is more serious than I thought.
显然 你母亲迷上了你
Apparently, your mother is amorously infatuated with you,
而不是你父亲
instead of your father.
等一等
Whoa. Wait a minute, Doc.
你是说我妈妈喜欢上我了?
Are you trying to tell me that my mother has got the hots for me?
正是!
Precisely.
噢..."严重"了!
Whoa. This is heavy.
你又说那个字眼: "很重"
There's that word again. "Heavy."
为什么每件事都"很重"?
Why are things so heavy in the future?
是不是未来的地心引力出了问题?
Is there a problem with the Earth's gravitational pull?
唯一让他们结婚的办法
What? The only way we're going to get those two to successfully mate
是让他们独处
is if they're alone together,
让他们多交流
so you've got to get your father and mother to interact
通过某些社交活动...
in some sort of social...
- 你意思是 一个约会? - 对!
- What? You mean like a date? - Right!
- 什么样的约会? - 我可不知道
- What kind of date? - I don't know.
50年代的孩子都干些什么?
What do kids do in the '50s?
他们是你的父母 你该知道的
They're your parents. You must know them.
他们的共同兴趣是什么?
What are their common interests?
喜欢一起做什么?
What do they like to do together?
没有
Nothing.
看! 有个舞会要来了
Look! There's a rhythmic ceremonial ritual coming up.
没错! 就是"海中魅力舞会"
Of course! The Enchantment Under the Sea dance!
他们在那里约会
They're supposed to go to this.
在那第一次接吻
That's where they kiss for the first time.
很好 孩子
All right, kid.
好好看着你父亲
You stick to your father like glue
一定要把他带到舞会上去
and make sure he takes her to that dance.
乔治 老兄
George, buddy.
记得我给你介绍的那个女孩吗? 洛莲?
Remember that girl I introduced you to, Lorraine?
你在写什么?
What are you writing?
哦...小说
Uh... Stories.
是关于...天外来客
Science fiction stories about visitors
从另一个行星来到地球
coming down to Earth from other planets.
少来了 我不知道 你还有这样的想象力
Get out of town! I didn't know you did anything creative.
给我看看?
Let me read some.
噢 不 不 不
Oh. No, no, no, no.
我从不让别人看我的小说
I never let anybody read my stories.
为什么?
Why not?
如果他们不喜欢?
Well, what if they didn't like them?
如果他们说我很糟?
What if they told me I was no good?
这很难让人理解的
I guess that would be pretty hard for somebody to understand.
不...一点也不难
No. No, not hard at all.
不管怎样 乔治 关于洛莲
So, anyway, George. About Lorraine.
她很喜欢你
She really likes you.
她要我告诉你 要你邀请她去
She told me to tell you that she wants you to ask her
"海中魅力舞会"
to the Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
- 真的? - 是的!
- Really? - Oh, yeah.
你只过去去邀请她就行了
All you got to do is go over there and ask her.
什么? 就在这餐厅里?
What? Right here, right now, in the cafeteria?
要是她不答应呢?
What if she said no?
我不知道 是否受得了这样的拒绝
I don't know if I could take that kind of a rejection.
而且 我想她宁愿另一个人去
Besides, I think she'd rather go with somebody else.
谁?
Who?
贝夫
Biff.
亲热一下
Don't kid around. Come on.
你想干什么?
I'm gonna leave.
你知道 你喜欢这样
You want it. You know you want it.
你想要的
You know you want me to give it to you.
住嘴! 我才不是那种女孩
Shut your filthy mouth. I'm not that kind of girl.
你是的 只不过你还不知道
Maybe you are and you just don't know it yet.
放开我!
Get your meat hooks off of me.
你听到了
You heard her.
她要你放开她!
She said, get your meat hooks off.
请
Please.
关你什么事 呆小子!
So what's it to you, butthead?
你这是欠揍
You know, you been looking for a fight.
看在你是新来的份上 我放过你 只是今天
Since you're new here, I'm going to cut you a break, today.
现在给我从这里滚出去
So, why don't you make like a tree and get out of here.
乔治!
George!
为什么你老跟着我?
Why do you keep following me around?
嘿 乔治! ... 我在和你说话呢!
Look, George... I'm telling you, George,
如果你不邀请洛莲去跳舞
if you do not ask Lorraine to that dance,
你会后悔一辈子的
I'm gonna regret it for the rest of my life.
可是我不能去跳舞
But I can't go to the dance.
那会错过我最喜欢的电视节目《科幻小说剧场》
I'll miss my favorite television program, Science Fiction Theatre.
但 乔治...洛莲想要和你一起去
Yeah, but, George, Lorraine wants to go with you.
给她一次机会
Give her a break.
我可没打算和洛莲跳舞
Look, I'm just not ready to ask Lorraine out to the dance,
为什么你们每个人
and not you or anybody else on this planet
都想要改变我的意愿呢?
is going to make me change my mind.
科幻小说剧场?
Science Fiction Theatre.
(科幻小说)
(前卫音乐)
你是谁?
Who are you?
别说话 地球人
Silence, Earthling.
我名叫达斯·维达(星球大战人物)
My name is Darth Vader.
我是飞鹰星来的外星人
I am an extraterrestrial from the planet Vulcan.
马丁!
Marty!
马丁! 马丁!
Marty! Marty!
乔治
Hey, George, buddy.
你没上学? 这一整天你做什么了?
You weren't at school. What have you been doing all day?
我睡过头了 我需要你的帮助
I overslept. Look, I need your help.
我必须邀请洛莲
I have to ask Lorraine out,
可我不知道该怎么做
but I don't know how to do it.
好了 喘口气 她在咖啡店里
All right. Okay, listen, keep your pants on. She's over in the cafe.
天啊...
God! How do you...
你怎么改变主意了?
What made you change your mind, George?
昨晚 从飞鹰星来了个外星人
Last night, Darth Vader came down from Planet Vulcan
他告诉我 如果我不邀请洛莲 他就熔化我的脑袋
and told me that if I didn't take Lorraine out, that he'd melt my brain.
我们保守这个秘密 好吗?
Let's just keep this brain-melting stuff to ourselves, okay?
好的 好
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
好的 好 她在那 乔治
All right, okay. There she is, George.
进去 邀请她
Now just go in there and invite her.
可我不知道该说些什么
Okay. But I don't know what to say.
说什么都行 乔治
Just say anything, George.
自然点儿 说你想到的第一句话
Say whatever's natural, the first thing that comes into your mind.
可我脑子里空空如也
Nothing's coming to my mind.
天哪 我怎么会出生的啊?
Jesus, George, it's a wonder I was even born.
什么?
What? What?
没什么...没什么
Nothing. Nothing. Nothing.
比如 跟她说 是命运让你们相遇
Look, tell her destiny brought you together.
她是你所见过
Tell her that she is the most beautiful girl
最美丽的女孩
you have ever seen in the world.
女孩总喜欢这样的话
Girls like that stuff.
你在干什么?
What are you doing, George?
我要记下来 这些话很不错
I'm writing this down. This is good stuff.
我们走
Yeah. Okay, let's go.
- 整整头发 - 我准备好了
- Can you take care of that? - Right.
给我一杯牛奶
Lou, give me a milk.
加巧克力
Chocolate.
洛莲 命运将我带给了你
Lorraine. My density has popped me to you.
什么?
What?
噢 我意思是...
What I meant to say was...
等一等 我见过你
Wait a minute. Don't I know you from somewhere?
对
Yes.
对 我是乔治 乔治·麦佛莱
Yes. I'm George. George McFly.
我是你的"密度"
I'm your density.
我是说
I mean,
我是你的命运
your destiny.
嘿 麦佛莱!
Hey, McFly.
该死!
Shit
我告诉过你 别到这来
I thought I told you never to come in here.
谁花你的钱?
Well, it's going to cost you.
你身上有多少钱?
How much money you got on you?
你要多少 贝夫?
How much do you want, Biff?
好啊 呆子
All right, punk.
现在 我要...
Now I'm going to...
贝夫 那是什么?
Whoa, whoa, Biff. What's that?
是 卡尔文·克雷恩 噢 我的天 真像梦一样
That's Calvin Klein. Oh, my God, he's a dream.
孩子 停下
Kid! Kid, stop! Stop!
嘿!
Hey!
待会还你
I'll get it back to you, all right?
你弄坏了!
You broke it!
回来!
Come back here!
看他!
Wow. Look at him go!
抓住他!
Get him!
快追车!
To the car! Go! Go!
他在什么东西上面?
What's that thing he's on?
一块有轮子的板
It's a board with wheels.
他真是白马王子
He's an absolute dream.
快啊!
Come on, come on!
追上那辆车!
Look out for the car!
我要宰了他
I'm going to ram him.
见鬼!
Shit!
(肥料车)
谢谢 孩子
Thanks a lot, kid.
我要找那狗娘养的算帐
I'm going to get that son of a bitch.
他从哪来?
Where does he come from?
是啊 他住在哪?
Yeah, where does he live?
不知道 但我会找出来的
I don't know, but I'm going to find out.
上帝
Oh, my God.
他们是怎么找到我的?
They found me. I don't know how, but they found me.
马丁 快跑!
Run for it, Marty!
上帝
Oh, my God.
他们是怎么找到我的?
They found me. I don't know how, but they found me.
马丁 快跑!
Run for it, Marty!
博士?
Doc?
嗨 马丁 我没听到你进来
Hi, Marty. I didn't hear you come in.
很有趣的机器...录像机
Fascinating device, this video unit.
听着 博士
Listen, Doc.
有些事情要告诉你
You know, there's something
关于那晚...
I haven't told you about the night
- 我们拍的录像 - 马丁 别告诉我
- we made that tape. - Please, Marty, don't tell me.
关于我命运的事
No man should know too much about his own destiny.
- 你不明白 - 我当然明白
- You don't understand. - I do understand.
对自己的命运知道太多
If I know too much about my own future,
我就不会为生存而努力了
I can endanger my own existence.
就像你和大自然斗争一样
Just as you've endangered yours.
你说得对...
You're right. Now...
给你看看送你回家的计划
Let me show you my plan for sending you home.
抱歉 这模型有点粗糙
Please excuse the crudity of this model.
我没时间做精确比例 上颜色
I didn't have time to build it to scale or paint it.
- 很不错 - 谢谢 谢谢
- It's good. - Thank you. Thank you.
好 现在
Okay, now.
我们使用工业电线
We run some industrial-strength electrical cable
从钟楼的顶部
from the top of the clock tower
牵到街上
down, suspending it over the street
两灯柱之间
between these two lamp posts.
同时 我们把时间机器
Meanwhile, we've outfitted the time vehicle
这的竿子 和钩子连接
with this big pole and hook,
直达通量电容器
which runs directly into the flux capacitor.
在计算好的时间 你从街头出发
At the calculated moment, you start off from down the street,
驶向电线
driving directly toward the cable,
加速至时速 88 英里
accelerating to 88 miles per hour.
据传单上说 本周六晚 10:04
According to the flyer, at precisely 10:04 p.m. This Saturday night,
闪电将准时击中钟楼
lightning will strike the clock tower, electrifying the cable
电线正好在那时与钩子接触
just as the connecting hook makes contact
将 1.21 兆瓦电力导入通量电容器
thereby sending 1.21 gigawatts into the flux capacitor
把你送回1985年
and sending you back to 1985.
好了 看好
All right, now. Watch this.
你把这小车上紧然后放手
You wind up the car and release it.
我模拟闪电
I'll simulate the lightning.
准备好
Ready.
开始
Set.
放手
Release.
你刚才不是很有信心吗 博士?
You're instilling me with a lot of confidence, Doc.
别担心 这个我来处理
Don't worry. I'll take care of the lightning.
你注意好你的父亲就是了
You take care of your pop.
对了 今天进展如何? 他约她出去了吗?
By the way, what happened today? Did he ask her out?
我想是的
I think so.
她说什么了吗?
What did she say?
是你母亲 她找到你了!
It's your mom! She's tracked you down!
把车盖好
Quick! Let's cover the time machine.
嗨 马丁
Hi, Cal... Marty.
妈妈...洛莲
Mom. Lorraine.
你怎么知道我在这?
How did you know I was here?
我跟踪你
I followed you.
这是我的博士...
Oh. This is my doc...
我叔叔 布朗博士
My uncle, Doc Brown.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
马丁 我知道这有点早
Marty, this may seem a little forward,
我想 你是否会邀请我
but I was kind of wondering if you'd ask me
参加星期六的"魅力海洋舞会"
to the Enchantment Under the Sea dance on Saturday.
你是说 还没人邀请你吗?
Wow, you mean... You mean nobody's asked you?
是的 还没有
No. Not yet.
那乔治呢?
What about George?
乔治·麦佛莱?
George McFly?
他很可爱 但你知道...
He's kind of cute and all, but not...
我要的是强壮的男人
Well, I think a man should be strong,
能靠自己站起来
so he can stand up for himself
去保护他心爱的女人
and protect the woman he loves.
你不是吗?
Don't you?
是的
Yeah.
我还是不明白
I still don't understand.
我怎么和她去跳舞呢?
How am I supposed to go to the dance with her
她不是要和你跳吗?
if she's already going to the dance with you?
因为 乔治 她想和你一起去
Well, because, George, she wants to go with you.
只是她自己还不知道
She just doesn't know it yet.
所以 我们要让她知道
That's why we got to show her
你 乔治·麦佛莱 是个勇士
that you, George McFly, are a fighter.
是个能自己站起来
You're somebody who's gonna stand up for yourself,
并且能保护她的人
somebody who's gonna protect her.
可我这辈子还没打过架呢
Yeah, but I've never picked a fight in my entire life.
你不是去打架 爸爸
Look, you're not going to be picking a fight, Dad.
爸爸...老兄
Daddy-o.
你是去拯救她 不是吗?
You're coming to her rescue, right?
好的 再重复一次我的计划
Okay, let's go over the plan again.
8:55 你去哪?
8:55, where are you going to be?
我去舞会
I'm going to be at the dance.
那么我去哪?
Right. And where am I going to be?
你和她一起呆在车里
You're gonna be in the car with her.
很好 9:00
Right, okay. So, right around 9:00,
她就会对我感到恼火
she's going to get very angry with me.
为什么她会恼火?
Why is she going to get angry with you?
因为 乔治 当男孩占她们便宜的时候
Well, because, George, nice girls get angry
好女孩 总是会生气
when guys take advantage of them.
你意思是 你要碰她...
You mean you're going to go touch her on her...
不 不 乔治
No. No, George, look.
只是表演 对吧?
It's just an act, right?
那么 9:00 你就到停车场
Okay. So, 9:00, you're strolling through the parking lot.
你会看到车里有争斗
You see us struggling in the car.
你走过来 拉开车门 说...
You walk up, you open the door, and you say...
你的台词 乔治
Your line, George.
你! 把那该死的手从她身上拿开!
Hey, you, get your damn hands off her!
我必须诅咒吗?
You really think I ought to swear?
对 干脆点!
Yes, definitely.
该死的 诅咒
God damn it, George, swear.
很好! 你走过来
Okay. So, now you come up.
揍我的肚子
You punch me in the stomach.
然后我逃了
I'm out for the count, right?
你和洛莲 从此将幸福的生活在一起
And you and Lorraine live happily ever after.
你说起来很简单
You make it sound so easy.
我只希望不会感到点怕
I just... I wish I wasn't so scared.
乔治 没什么好怕的
George, there's nothing to be scared of.
只需要一点自信
All it takes is a little self-confidence.
你知道 "只要一心一意
You know, if you put your mind to it,
做什么都成"
you can accomplish anything.
山谷镇周六晚天气预报
...Hill Valley area weather this Saturday night.
晴朗 有些许云彩
Mostly clear, with some scattered clouds.
气温40度左右
Lows tonight in the upper 40s.
你肯定暴风雨一定会来吗?
Are you sure about this storm?
别相信天气预报 更别提未来了
Since when can weathermen predict the weather, let alone the future?
马丁 看到你走 我很伤心
You know, Marty, I'm going to be very sad to see you go.
你改变了我的生命
You've really made a difference in my life.
给了我奋斗的目标
You've given me something to shoot for.
想想看 我会活着看到1985年
Just knowing that I'm going to be around to see 1985.
我会成功的发明这个!
That I'm going to succeed in this!
我将有机会穿越时光!
That I'm going to have a chance to travel through time!
要经过30年漫长等待 我才能再和你谈
It's going to be really hard waiting 30 years before I can talk to you
这三天发生的事情
about everything that's happened in the past few days.
我会想念你的 马丁
I'm really going to miss you, Marty.
我也一样
I'm really going to miss you.
博士 关于未来...
Doc, about the future...
不!
No!
马丁 我们已经认同了
Marty! We've already agreed
知道未来的事情
that having information about the future
是相当危险的
can be extremely dangerous.
尽管你一片好心
Even if your intentions are good,
但结果也许相反的
it can backfire drastically.
你所要告诉我的
Whatever you've got to tell me,
我会通过时间理解
I'll find out through the natural course of time.
"亲爱的布朗博士
"Dear Dr. Brown.
在我回去的那晚
On the night that I go back in time,
你会
you will be
被恐怖分子枪杀
shot by terrorists.
请采取防范措施
Please take whatever precautions are necessary
防止这可怕的事情发生
to prevent this terrible disaster.
你的朋友
Your friend,
马丁"
Marty."
(请在 1985年开封)
晚上好 布朗博士 这电线干什么用的?
'Evening, Dr. Brown. What's with the wire?
噢 只是个气象实验
Oh, just a little weather experiment.
这里面是什么?
What you got under here?
别 别碰!
No! Don't touch that!
这是非常敏感的气象传感器
Some new, specialized weather-sensing equipment.
你有许可证吗?
You got a permit for that?
当然有
Of course I do.
等一等 待我查看
Just a second. Let me see if I can find it here.
(魅力海洋舞会)
你介不介意我们停车...亲热一阵?
Do you mind if we park for a while?
好主意 我喜欢在车里亲热
That's a great idea. I'd love to park.
马丁 我快18岁了
Marty, I'm almost 18 years old.
我并不是从来没跟人在车里亲热过
It's not like I've never parked before.
什么?
What?
马丁 你很紧张 出什么事了?
Marty, you seem so nervous. Is something wrong?
不 没有
No.
洛莲 洛莲 你在干什么?
Lorraine! Lorraine, what are you doing?
我从老妈酒柜里弄到的
I swiped it from the old lady's liquor cabinet.
知道吗 你不能喝酒
Yeah, well, you shouldn't drink.
为什么不?
Why not?
因为你...
Because you...
会为此后悔一辈子
You might regret it later in life.
别这么保守!
Marty, don't be such a square.
这里人人都喝酒
Everybody who's anybody drinks.
天啊 你还抽烟?
Jeez, you smoke, too?
你开始像我妈妈了
Marty, you're beginning to sound just like my mother.
休息一会儿
We're going to take a little break,
我们很快就回来
but we'll be back in a while,
大家请别走开
so don't nobody go nowhere.
马丁? 为什么你这么紧张?
Marty? Why are you so nervous?
洛莲
Lorraine.
你是否遇到过这样的情况
Have you ever been in a situation
你要做一件事情
where you knew you had to act a certain way,
当事到临头 却不知
but when you got there, you didn't know
如何是好?
if you could go through with it?
你是说 第一次约会不知该怎么做吗?
You mean like how you're supposed to act on a first date?
也可以这么说
Sort of.
我想我很清楚你的意思
I think I know exactly what you mean.
真的吗?
You do?
在那情况下我怎样做 你知道吗?
You know what I do in those situations?
怎样?
What?
我才不担心
I don't worry.
全错了 我不知道为什么
This is all wrong. I don't know what it is.
但我吻你 就像是在吻...
But when I kiss you, it's like I'm kissing
我的弟弟
my brother.
没有任何感觉 对吗?
I guess that doesn't make any sense, does it?
当然有 感觉相当不错
Believe me, it makes perfect sense.
有人来了
Somebody's coming.
你害我花了300美元修车费 你这个狗娘养的!
You caused 300 bucks damage to my car, you son of a bitch.
我要让你的屁股来偿还!
And I'm going to take it out of your ass. Hold him.
让他走 贝夫 你醉了!
Let him go, Biff. You're drunk.
瞧 谁在这啊?
Well, look-ey what we have here.
别走 到我这来
No, no! You're staying right here with me. Come on, Lorraine.
放开我!
Let me go!
放开她 你这杂种!
Leave her alone, you bastard!
把他带到后面去 我马上来
Take him in back, all right? I'll be right there.
别害臊啊
Just admit that you want it. Come on.
快去 有什么好看的!
Well, go on. This ain't no peep show.
有辆车
Hey, let's put him in there.
这就是弄坏我头发的代价
That's for messing up my hair.
你们在我车里干什么?
What the hell are you doing to my car?
黑鬼 这没你的事!
Hey, beat it, spook. This don't concern you.
喊谁黑鬼呢 你这呆瓜
Who you calling "spook," peckerwood?
嘿 嘿 听着 伙计...
Hey, hey, listen, guys...
听我说 我可不想找麻烦
Look, I don't want to mess with no reefer addicts, okay?
回去找你们的母亲去!
Get home to your mama, boy.
贝夫!
Biff!
快 贝夫!
Hurry, Biff!
放我出去! 救救我!
Let me out of here!
我的钥匙在哪?
Reginald, where are your keys?
在行李箱里
The keys are in the trunk.
再说一遍?
Say that again?
我说钥匙就在我这里
I said, the keys are in here.
来嘛!
Come on!
你! 把那该死的手拿开!
Hey, you, get your damn hands off...
你弄错车子了吧 麦佛莱?
I think you got the wrong car, McFly.
乔治 救救我 求你了!
George, help me! Please!
转过身 然后走开
Just turn around, McFly, and walk away.
乔治 救救我
Please, George.
你聋了吗 麦佛莱?
Are you deaf, McFly?
关上车门 转过身去!
Close the door and beat it.
不 贝夫! 你放开她
No, Biff. You leave her alone.
好啊 麦佛莱!
All right, McFly.
这可是你自找的
You're asking for it, and now you're going to get it.
贝夫 住手!
Biff, stop it!
你要把他的手弄断了
Biff, you'll break his arm!
贝夫 不!
Biff, no!
来帮个忙
Give me a hand here, Reginald.
见鬼 我的手刮伤了!
Damn it, man! I sliced my hand!
- 谁的钥匙? - 我的
- Whose are these? - Mine.
谢谢
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
你要把他的手弄断了!
You're going to break his arm!
贝夫 放开他!
Biff! Biff, leave him alone!
让他走吧!
Let him go! Let him go!
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
那家伙是谁?
Who is that guy?
乔治·麦佛莱
That's George McFly.
那个 乔治·麦佛莱 吗?
That's George McFly?
借过
Excuse me.
暴风雨
The storm.
嘿 伙计 你们得回去 完成演奏
Hey, guys, you gotta get back in there and finish the dance.
伙计 看马文的手
Hey, man. Look at Marvin's hand.
他不能弹吉他了
He can't play with his hand like that,
我们不能没有他
and we can't play without him.
马文 你必须去演奏
Yeah, well. Look, Marvin, you got to play.
这是他们第一次站在舞池里接吻
See, that's where they kiss for the first time on the dance floor.
没音乐他们就没法跳舞了
And if there's no music, they can't dance.
不跳舞 他们就不会接吻
If they can't dance, they can't kiss.
不接吻 他们就不会相恋 那我就完蛋了
If they can't kiss, they can't fall in love and I'm history.
伙计 舞会完了
Hey, man, the dance is over
除非你找到别人演奏吉他
unless you know somebody else that can play the guitar.
这首曲子献给所有情人
This is for all you lovers out there.
∮ 凡间天使 凡间天使 ∮
∮ Earth angel, Earth angel ∮
∮ 你会是我的吗 ∮
∮ Will you be mine? ∮
∮ 我亲爱的 ∮
∮ My darling dear ∮
乔治 你要吻我吗?
George, aren't you going to kiss me?
我不知道
I don't know.
走开 乔治·麦佛莱!
Scram, McFly. I'm cutting in.
∮ 人间天使 人间天使 ∮
∮ Earth angel, Earth angel ∮
∮ 我喜欢的那个 ∮
∮ The one I adore ∮
孩子 你还好吗?
Hey, boy, you all right?
我没法演奏了
I can't play.
乔治!
George!
乔治
George.
对不起
Excuse me.
∮ 你对幸福的憧憬 ∮
∮ The vision of your happiness ∮
∮ 凡间天使 凡间天使 ∮
∮ Earth angel, Earth angel ∮
∮ 请属于我 ∮
∮ Please be mine ∮
∮ 我亲爱的 ∮
∮ My darling dear ∮
∮ 永远爱你 ∮
∮ Love you for all time ∮
∮ 我是傻瓜 ∮
∮ I'm just a fool ∮
∮ 爱上你的 ∮
∮ A fool in love ∮
∮ 傻瓜 ∮
∮ with you ∮
再来一曲?
Yeah, man, that was good. Let's do another one.
不行 我得走了
No. I got to go.
不要这样 伙计 该来一首特别的
Come on, man. Let's do something that really cooks.
一首"特别"的...
Something that cooks.
这才象话嘛
All right.
这才象话嘛!
All right!
好吧
All right.
好吧 这是首老歌...
All right, this is an oldie, but...
是我那个时代的老歌
Well, it's an oldie where I come from.
把调定在 布鲁斯 b 调上
All right, guys, listen, this is a blues riff in B.
注意变调 要跟上我
Watch me for the changes, and try and keep up, okay?
∮ 在新奥尔良路易斯安那的路上 ∮
∮ Way down in Louisiana Down in New Orleans ∮
∮ 回到常青树丛中的树林里 ∮
∮ Way back up in the woods among the evergreens ∮
∮ 那里有一个用泥土和木头建造的小木屋 ∮
∮ There stood a log cabin made of earth and wood ∮
∮ 那里住着一个叫约翰尼·B·古德的乡下男孩 ∮
∮ Where lived a country boy name of Johnny B. Goode ∮
∮ 他从来没有学过读书写字 ∮
∮ He never ever learned to read or write so well ∮
∮ 他会弹吉他 就像他在敲钟一样 ∮
∮ He could play the guitar just like he's ringing a bell ∮
∮ 去吧 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Go, Johnny, go, go ∮
∮ 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Johnny, go, go, go ∮
∮ 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Johnny, go, go ∮
乔治 听说你摆平了贝夫 干得漂亮!
Hey, George, I heard you laid out Biff. Nice going.
乔治 你有没有想过竞选班代表?
George, you ever think of running for class president?
∮ 约翰尼·B·古德 ∮
∮ Johnny B. Goode ∮
∮ 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Johnny, go, go ∮
∮ 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Johnny, go, go, go ∮
∮ 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Johnny, go, go ∮
∮ 去吧 约翰尼 去吧 去吧 去吧 ∮
∮ Go, Johnny, go, go, go ∮
∮ 约翰尼·B·古德 ∮
∮ Johnny B. Goode ∮
乔希 乔希 是我
Chuck! Chuck, it's Marvin.
你表兄马文·贝利
Your cousin, Marvin Berry.
你不是要全新的音乐吗?
You know that new sound you're looking for?
来听这个!
Well, listen to this.
你们现在还不能接受这个
I guess you guys aren't ready for that yet.
但你们的孩子会喜欢的
But your kids are going to love it.
洛莲!
Lorraine.
马丁 曲子很有趣
Marty, that was very interesting music.
是啊
Yeah.
希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind,
乔治要送我回家
but George asked if he could take me home.
棒极了 洛莲!
Great! Good. Good, Lorraine.
你有那种感觉了?
I had a feeling about you two.
是的 我感觉到了
I have a feeling, too.
我得走了
Listen, I got to go,
我得告诉你 这段时间 很有教育意义
but I wanted to tell you that it's been educational.
马丁 我们还会见面吗?
Marty, will we ever see you again?
我保证会的
I guarantee it.
马丁 感谢你的忠告
Well, Marty, I want to thank you for all your good advice.
我不会忘记的
I'll never forget it.
好的 乔治
Right, George.
祝你们好运
Well, good luck, you guys.
还有一件事 如果你们有了孩子
One other thing. If you guys ever have kids,
其中的一个在8岁的时候
and one of them, when he's eight years old,
不慎烧坏了客厅的地毯
accidentally sets fire to the living room rug,
别对他太严厉
go easy on him.
好的
Okay.
"马丁" 多好的名字
Marty. Such a nice name.
见鬼! 那孩子到哪去了?
Damn! Where is that kid?
见鬼!
Damn!
见鬼! 见鬼!
Damn! Damn!
你迟到了 你有没有时间概念啊?
You're late! Do you have no concept of time?
别这样 我得换件衣服
Hey, come on. I had to change.
你以为我能穿这样的衣服回去吗?
Do you think I'm going back in that zoot suit?
我爸爸他成功了
The old man really came through. It worked.
他一拳摆平了贝夫
He laid out Biff in one punch.
我也不知道他怎么做到的
I didn't know he had it in him.
他一辈子从来没有这样
He's never stood up to Biff in his life.
从来没有吗?
Never?
是的! 怎么了?
No. Why? What's the matter?
好了 让我们现在定目标时间
All right! Let's set your destination time.
这是你离开的时间
This is the exact time you left.
我要把你送回到相同的时间
Let's send you back at exactly the same time.
就跟你一直没离开一样
It'll be like you never left.
我在街道的那边涂了白线
Now, I painted a white line on the street way over there.
那是你的出发地点
That's where you'll start from.
我精确计算了距离
I've calculated the precise distance,
还考虑了加速度
taking into account the acceleration speed
以及风阻力的影响
and wind resistance retroactive
在你到达的时候 闪电刚好发生
from the moment the lightning strikes,
准确的说 是7分22秒之后
which will be in exactly 7 minutes and 22 seconds.
当钟响的时候 你就发动车子
When this alarm goes off, you hit the gas.
好了!
Right.
我想 都准备好了
Well, I guess that's everything.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你
Thank you.
30 年后见
See you in about 30 years.
但愿如此
I hope so.
别担心!
Don't worry!
当你以时速88英里
As long as you hit that wire
接触到电线的时候
with the connecting hook at precisely 88 miles an hour,
闪电刚好击中钟楼
the instant the lightning strikes the tower
一切都会顺利的
everything will be fine.
谢谢
Right.
这是什么意思?
What's the meaning of this?
30年后你会知道的
You'll find out in 30 years.
这是关于未来的吧?
It's about the future, isn't it?
这是关于未来的
It's information about the future.
等一等
Wait a minute.
我警告过你的
I warned you about this, kid.
这会导致因果关系的严重灾难!
The consequences could be disastrous!
你必须冒这个险
Doc, that's a risk you're going to have to take.
这关系到你的生命!
Your life depends on it!
不!
No!
我拒绝接受
I refuse to accept the responsibility.
既然这样 我就直接告诉你
In that case, I'll tell you straight out.
天啊!
Great Scott!
你拿电线 我上去用绳子拉
You get the cable, I'll throw the rope down to you.
明白!
Right! I got it!
博士!
Doc!
快点! 快点!
Come on, come on. Let's go!
好了! 拉吧!
All right! Take it up!
拉呀!
Go!
博士!
Doc!
什么?
What?
我必须告诉你未来的事情!
I have to tell you about the future.
什么?
What?
我必须告诉你未来的事情!
I have to tell you about the future!
什么?
What?
在我回去的那晚 你会被...
On the night I go back in time, you get...
博士!
Doc!
快去!
Go!
不!
No, Doc!
看时间!
Look at the time!
你还有不到4分钟了! 快去! 快去!
You've got less than four minutes. Please, hurry!
耶!
Yeah!
见鬼! 博士 为什么你要撕碎那封信?
Damn it, Doc! Why did you have to tear up that letter?
没时间了
If I only had more time.
等一等 我有的是时间
Wait a minute. I got all the time I want.
我有时间机器 我可以早点回去通知他
I got a time machine. I can just go back early and warn him.
好 10分钟该足够了
Okay. Ten minutes ought to do it.
时间电路打开 通量电容器
Okay. Time circuit's on. Flux capacitor, fluxing.
引擎启动 很好!
Engine running. All right.
不! 不!
No. No, no.
快呀! 别出乱子 快呀!
Come on. Not this time. Come on. Come on.
快呀!
Come on.
发动吧! 快!
Here we go. Here we go. This time. Come on.
快啊!
Please. Please. Come on!
博士
Doc.
疯狂的酒鬼!
Crazy drunk driver.
好了
All right. Fred.
棒极了
You look great. Everything looks great.
1:24 还有时间 我来也 博士!
1:24. I still got time. I'm coming, Doc!
别这样!
No! No, not again! Come on! Come on!
利比亚人!
Libyans.
不!
No!
混蛋!
You bastard!
快!
Go!
博士 博士!
Doc! Doc!
不! 不!
No! No!
你还活着!
You're alive.
防弹衣?
Bulletproof vest?
你是怎么知道的?
How did you know?
我没机会告诉你呀
I never got a chance to tell you.
你不是说会影响未来事件?
What about all that talk about screwing up future events?
破坏时空连续性?
The space-time continuum?
我想 让这理论见鬼去吧
Well, I figured, what the hell?
那么 你要去哪?
So, how far ahead are you going?
30年之后 很不错的整数字
About 30 years. It's a nice, round number.
记得去看看我 那时我47岁了
Look me up when you get there, all right? Guess I'll be about 47.
我会的
I will.
多保重
Take care.
你也是
You, too.
再见 爱因斯坦
Right. Bye-bye, Einie.
对了 刚到的时候当心点 有些颠簸
Oh. And watch that re-entry. It's a little bumpy.
好的
You bet.
真是场恶梦
What a nightmare.
要是爸爸打电话过来 告诉他我今晚要加班
If Paul calls me, tell him I'm working at the boutique late tonight.
琳达 我可不是你的电话答录员
Linda, first of all, I'm not your answering service,
有个克雷或是格雷
second of all, somebody named Greg
不久之前打电话给你
or Craig called you just a little while ago.
是哪一个? 克雷还是格雷 ?
Well, which one was it, Greg or Craig?
我不知道 你男友太多了 我可记不住
I don't know! I can't keep up with all of your boyfriends.
嘿
Hey.
这到底是怎么回事?
What the hell is this?
是早餐啊
Breakfast.
你昨晚穿着这身衣服睡觉吗?
Did you sleep in your clothes again last night?
没错...
Yeah. I...
你怎么这身打扮 戴夫?
Yeah. What are you wearing, Dave?
马丁 我一向穿着西服去办公室啊
Marty, I always wear a suit to the office.
- 你还好吗? - 是的
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
我想我们得重赛
I think we need a rematch, George.
重赛?
A rematch?
你以为我在作弊?
Why? Were you cheating?
不
No.
喂 早上好!
Hello. Good morning.
妈妈 爸爸!
Mom! Dad!
- 伤到头没有? - 马丁! 没事吧
- Did you hit your head? - Marty, are you all right?
你们气色真不错! 妈妈你真苗条!
You guys look great. Mom, you look so thin.
- 谢谢 马丁 - 乔治!
- Why, thank you, Marty. - George!
早上好 瞌睡虫
Good morning, sleepyhead.
早上好 戴夫 琳达
Good morning, Dave. Linda.
早上好 妈妈
Good morning, Mom.
我差点忘了 詹尼弗·帕克 来过电话
Marty, I almost forgot. Jennifer Parker called.
我很喜欢她 马丁 她是个可爱的女孩
I sure like her, Marty. She is such a sweet girl.
今晚是个重要的约会 对吗?
Isn't tonight the night of the big date?
什么?
What? What, Ma?
你们今晚不是要去湖边吗?
Aren't you going up to the lake tonight?
你为此已计划两周了
You've been planning it for two weeks.
妈妈 我们谈过这件事了 可我怎么去湖边呢?
Mom, we talked about this. How can I go to the lake?
车不是撞坏了吗?
The car's wrecked.
撞坏? 撞坏?
Wrecked? Wrecked?
什么时候发生的? 怎么没人告诉我?
When did this happen? Why wasn't I told?
别吵了
Quiet down.
我肯定车子很好
I'm sure the car is fine.
为什么没人通知我?
Why am I always the last one to know about these things?
瞧 贝夫 正在给车打腊呢
See? There's Biff out there waxing it right now.
贝夫 弄得怎样了
Now, Biff, I want to make sure that
我要你打两层腊而不是一层
we get two coats of wax this time, not just one.
我刚刚打好了第二层
I'm just finishing up the second coat now.
贝夫 别骗我
Now, Biff, don't con me.
对不起 麦佛莱先生
I'm sorry, Mr. McFly.
我意思是 我刚刚开始打第二层
I meant I was just starting on the second coat.
贝夫就是这样 总是编故事
Biff. What a character. Always trying to get away with something.
我们在高中的时候就认识他了
I've had to stay on top of Biff ever since high school.
要不是他...
Although, if it wasn't for him...
我们还不会相爱呢
We never would have fallen in love.
没错
That's right.
麦佛莱 先生 麦佛莱 夫人 刚刚到的
Mr. McFly! Mr. McFly, this just arrived.
嗨 马丁! 我想是你的新书
Oh, hi, Marty. I think it's your new book.
亲爱的 你的第一部小说
Honey! Your first novel.
我告诉过你的
Like I've always told you,
"只要一心一意 做什么都成"
"you put your mind to it, you can accomplish anything."
马丁 你的钥匙
Oh, Marty, here's your keys.
已为今晚约会打好蜡了
You're all waxed up, ready for tonight.
钥匙?
Keys?
要不要兜兜风 先生?
How about a ride, mister?
詹尼弗
Jennifer.
真喜欢看到你 让我看看你
Oh, are you a sight for sore eyes! Let me look at you.
马丁 你好像一周没见我似的
Marty, you're acting like you haven't seen me in a week.
的确如此
I haven't.
你还好吗? 一切正常吗?
You okay? Is everything all right?
是的
Oh, yeah.
一切都太好了
Everything is great.
马丁! 你得和我回去!
Marty! You've got to come back with me!
去哪?
Where?
回到未来
Back to the future.
等一等 你在干什么 博士?
Wait a minute. What are you doing, Doc?
我需要燃料
I need fuel.
(高能转换器)
快上车
Go ahead. Quick! Get in the car.
不 不 不 博士 我才刚到这
No, no. Doc, I just got here, okay?
詹尼弗和我正要开车去兜风
Jennifer's here. We're gonna take the new truck for a spin.
把她带上 这事也和她有关
Well, bring her along. This concerns her, too.
等一等 你在说什么?
Wait a minute, Doc. What are you talking about?
未来发生什么事了?
What happens to us in the future?
是不是我们变成呆子或怎么了?
Do we become assholes or something?
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, Marty.
你和詹尼弗感情很好
Both you and Jennifer turn out fine.
是关于你们的孩子
It's your kids, Marty.
要帮他们办点事
Something has got to be done about your kids.
博士 我们得倒车 没有足够长的路 加速到时速88英里
Hey, Doc, we better back up. We don't have enough road to get up to 88.
路? 我们要去的地方 不需要路
Roads? Where we're going, we don't need roads.